Lorenzo Aceti

Full-Stack Software Engineer | React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.JS, Python, Django +55 21 965400438 | lorenzo.acetii@gmail.com | portfolio | linkedin | github

ABOUT ME

I'm a full-stack developer with over 2 years of experience specializing in the development of React, Django frameworks and their tools. Experienced in large projects, working interdisciplinary between design and software development sectors, as well as looking for product improvement solutions, such as refactorings and project structuring. I use fluent English for internal communication and with multinational clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Engineer Junior | ISDB FlowTech aug 2023 - present

Through the development of intelligent applications, ISDB FlowTech provides technical consulting solutions for the main Oil and Gas players in Brazil and abroad.

- Development of the front-end of the web applications.
- Development of the back-end of the Software-as-a-service applications.
- Improvement and contribution to the in-house computational and numerical libraries and repositories.
- Test and debugging of the web applications.
- Contribution to the configuration and design of databases and solutions architectures for the web applications.
- Started the migration process of a large-scale project for one of the biggest companies in Brazil, refactoring the frontend stack from React + Javascript to Next.js 13 and Typescript.

Tech Stack and skills: Next.JS, Typescript, Material UI, TailwindCSS, Django REST Framework, PostgreSQL

Full-Stack Developer Internship | ISDB FlowTech aug 2021 - aug 2023

This is where I started my professionalization process, where I learned important lessons in project management and the development of large-scale projects. I managed to stand out for my proactivity, accurate deliveries and high quality in software development.

- Started the frontend and backend development of a large-scale project for a big company, using React and TailwindCSS, libraries never used before by the team and that I myself suggested the implementation (in addition to Django in the backend).
- I worked on the creation of RESTful API's using the Django Rest Framework, a library that I myself suggested to implement in the project.
- I worked proactively in identifying and solving performance and security issues.
- I presented solutions for the implementation of new technologies that would bring significant impacts on the performance and security of the company's applications.
- Prototyped the entire design and choice of colors for a large-scale application.
- Developed advanced authentication systems, with JWT and email confirmations.

Tech Stack and skills: React, React Router, Styled Components, Tailwind CSS, Plotly, Data Analysis, Panda, PostgreSQL, Django MVC, Django REST Framework, Postman

SKILLS

- React Js (hooks, state management, accessibility and performance)
- Tailwind CSS & CSS in Js (styled components, Material UI(MUI))
- Saas (software as a service)
- Next Js (SSR, SSG, SEO)
- React router
- Django (MVC, Rest Framework)

- Javascript & TypeScript
- Git (versioning control)
- APIs Rest
- Agile teams experience
- Experience with design systems (figma & adobe products)
- Npm package managing
- Performance optimization

EDUCATION

Federal Fluminense University
Information Systems (Bachelor's degree)

2019 - 2023

RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

• New Class - Extensive CG (Adobe and Autodesk Authorized Training Center) RedZero Web Design, 2011-2014.

LANGUAGES

- English fluent
- Portuguese native